<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>squawk's site</title>
  <id>https://catsquawk.github.io/</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://catsquawk.github.io/feed.xml" />
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://catsquawk.github.io/" />
  <author>
    <name>Squawk</name>
  </author>
  <updated>2025-11-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Yapter One: Android apps, GTD, journaling, doing new stuff</title>
    <id>https://catsquawk.github.io/2025-11-24.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://catsquawk.github.io/2025-11-24.html" />
    <updated>2025-11-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <summary type="text">November 24th yap session</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello. Not sure what to type. I was thinking about all the things I'd talk about here, but now that I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; at my keyboard, it's all left me. I've been feeling a bit overwhelmed lately, like nothing's working right and everything's just broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to journal on a daily basis, until a few months ago. It became a form of procrastination to look through previous entries and talk about whatever I was thinking at that moment. It wasn't all bad, my writing's definitely improved and I can think a lot more clearly, but it ate through a lot of time that would have been more wisely used elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it also had this effect of stagnating progress (is that the right word?) in stuff I was struggling with. For instance, I wanted to learn how to study more effectively. Naturally, I double-clicked the Obsidian icon in the taskbar and started typing out my ideas. I'd then install a plugin (namely, the nomnoml one) and make a flowchart for that learning plan. Minutes turn into hours and I'm just fiddling with the plugin's settings and not doing any of the actual studying. I essentially fooled myself into thinking I was being productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I guess this was more a problem with note-taking apps (and software in general) being so feature-packed and fiddly that it's easy to lose sight of your original intention. On some days, I wouldn't have anything meaningful to think or write about (mostly because I scrolled YouTube Shorts the entire 24 hours) so I'd open the app solely to tweak CSS and mess with plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a post a while back on Bearblog (this it was called &amp;quot;the append and review note&amp;quot;?) which said that the usefulness of a note is directly proportional to how much you review and utilise it. My diary entries (think I should raise that point, all my writing was about my thoughts and feelings, so not really a journal) were never reviewed, at least for any good reason. It was all word vomit with no real use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also created something of an echo chamber. I wanted to make practicing David Allen's GTD a habit, but because every note I just talked about how I wasn't doing it right and needed to change something, but I never really actually &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; change anything. Just wrote about it. Me from two days ago was okay with it, so I am too.
It was all talk and no walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I understand that writing in itself wasn't at all the issue, moreso the lack of clear intention and action. Pausing the consistent journaling did allow me to make actual progress in things that are meaningful to me. To list them, I've:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gotten through the Python bit of Harvard's CS50 (almost, on the last lecture now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put GTD into practice and made it my own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started reading consistently again. I've read through all of &lt;em&gt;The Perfect Run&lt;/em&gt; (absolute peak web novel) and started &lt;em&gt;New Life as a Max-Level Archmage&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do still sometimes reach for my phone instead of my ereader, so I'm now halfway through Mark Smith's reading of &lt;em&gt;Sherlock Holmes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can kind of cook/bake. I only know how to make fries, pizza and raisin muffins but I'm learning new stuff consistently!&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chocolate chip cookies and brownies were a failure. Will retry them again sometime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistently reading the Quran again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started exercising with the primer on nick-e.com and morning jogs with my dad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last two are farily new, so I don't think I can really call them &amp;quot;consistent&amp;quot; yet, but you get the point. I also want to relearn drawing in a more structured fashion, so drawabox is on the list. My GTD implementation is in a small and simple Android app (&amp;quot;Another notes app&amp;quot; on F-Droid). It consists of a few tags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gtd: has my projects, someday and next actions (todo) list&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;todo list is in todotxt format, btw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;checklists: has my weekly review, shopping, file backups and in list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recipes: has my recipe's recorded in Markdown (the Grocery app has a spec on GitHub)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;journal: occasional journal entries&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;think I'll replace this with a single &amp;quot;scratchpad&amp;quot; note, there're like 5 notes and they're really just whiteboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;calendar: a note for each month in a simple format heavily inspired by the calendartxt spec on tero karvinen's site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really wanted a folder of text files and a text editor (Squircle CE is my choice) to work, since that's what I use for pretty much all writing on my laptop. It sucked on a phone. Each character taking up the same width meant that about 5 words fit on each line, and the wrapping just looked bad. You also can't easily run scripts on text files (don't want to use Termux) so any form sorting is out the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could probably get used to it, but I found apps with actual buttons and proportionally spaced text more comfortable by &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt;. Another notes is close enough, but gives me that inch of function I'd like for things to be smooth and convenient. It has two note types, checklists and plain text. I use the checklist notes for my todo list (since items can be sorted alphabetically) and my calendar (just for better spacing between items). The rest is plain text. The app's also just really buttery smooth and fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm aware that there are a plethora of other note taking apps that can do the same, and probably much more. Another notes is great though, it's really perfect for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, time to glaze another app: Automate. Not as much to say for this one, but it holds my GTD system together just as much. I have three flows set up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A capture flow, which opens a single-line input dialogue so I can quickly jot something down and hit enter to save it to a text file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An inbox processing flow, which opens a choice dialogue that lets me either copy everything in my inbox or clear the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A timer flow, which lets me input a number and then sets a timer for that many minutes.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MUCH easier then opening the clock app, clicking the timer button and hitting two extra zeros just to get the number in the minutes column.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There're not huge on their own, but map them to the volume buttons and the convenience is &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; (Key Mapper on F-Droid).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a few apps from F-Droid have made tech stuff &lt;em&gt;that much&lt;/em&gt; since I got my phone (August 9th, I think it was?):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KISS Launcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cromite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MJ PDF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NewPipe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VLC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voice (audiobook player)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quran.com's app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off the top of my head. There're probably 10 or so more. KISS is great, I can get to the apps I want quicker and the ones that have potential to distract me are hidden from view. Cromite's also cool, adblocking and userscripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, I really like my phone. It's a small and convenient thing that does everything I could possibly want it to. For the first month it was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; distracting, YouTube and Pokemon at my fingertips ate through &lt;em&gt;hours&lt;/em&gt; of my day. My screen time can still go up to 3 hours, but it mostly stays at around 2 and those hours are hours that I think are relatively well-spent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to journaling, the point I &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; to start this post off with was that I felt the need to start some writing again was because I started bottling up too much in my head. Sure, the actioning stuff goes into my GTD inbox, it's processed and voila, a todo list.
There are some ways to deal with more abstract things like stress (Facile Things' Medium blog talks about it), but they really just don't beat venting them out on paper or a text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have any friends, and family members don't want to hear any of it, so anything I feel gets pushed down and shut off the best I can. I tend to overthink things, probably due to how I was raised. After I started all these new things, the stuff that came up and worried me increased exponentially. I'm not trying to sound pitiful or anything, by the way. I realise that this is a very common issue, since I myself don't want to listen to other people yap about their issues. I find it quite hard to shrug things off though, at least compared to the few other people I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here. This won't really be a daily thing, probably twice a week, but it should help get things off my chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a bit nervous about how the things I've started will turn out in the long run. I wanted to be a storytime animator for a good portion of my life (9-14 years old) and there's currently a wave of new-gen animators popping up. It's become a trend of sorts, so a lucky few have gotten chunky headstarts in sub count (jasistaken and snoozie being the only two I can remember).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want to be an animator as much now, since I now see meaning in other things more than I do in drawing. But, I'm still a bit envious of them. I'd love to be an animator. I just don't want to have to cater to YouTube's algorithm or deal with the pressure of an audience just waiting for your next video. Online presence in general, I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work like that and expectations to fulfill are probably inevitable in life though, so maybe I should reconsider? I enjoy writing more than I do drawing, so I'd post fairly infrequently.
I might make an animation YouTube channel down the line, just for fun? Might not be a storytime one, might not get a following, but I'll be okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's kind of it. I wanted to talk about how I can get overwhelmed with the pressure of needing to complete what's on my todo list, but it's a thought I've chewed around in my brain long enough to not want to elaborate on it so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I should use todotxt's priorities slightly differently, to indicate what I aim to do today. I currently just use them to plan my next few actions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(A) Item 1
(B) Item 2
(C) Item 3
(D) Item 4
Item 5
Item 6
Item 7
Item 8
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priority D items could be today's stuff, whilst ABC stay the same?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevermind, my system works fine. I add priorities to 3-5 actions every evening, which are my todo list for the next day. If I complete those, cool, I can do some of the other actions present or just chill the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needed to reassure myself, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started tracking my calorie intake, trying to lose weight. Using my My Fitness Pal app (tried Nutritionix Track and Cronometer, like this one best) and I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; underestimated how much I eat. The app gave me a goal of 1620 each day, but I easily go over 2000!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good part is that the main offenders are easy to eliminate: food I ate when I wasn't hungry, bread and calorie-dense snacks. I think I'll be able to keep within limits tomorrow, I was really close today (1520 + whatever my dinner is, usually about 400 cals).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, that's really it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>